Finding Aid for Michigan Congress of Parents and Teachers records, 1891-1961
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Michigan Congress of Parents and Teachers records
1891-1961
Michigan Congress of Parents and Teachers.
851889 Bh 2; BH Outsize
Michigan branch of a national parent and teacher organization; organizational records include convention books, minutes of meetings, treasurer's reports, and scrapbooks.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
18 linear feet
6 oversize volumes
The record group is on deposit from the organization (donor no. 3922 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The National Congress of Parents and Teachers was organized in Washington DC in February 1897. The Michigan Congress of Parents and Teachers was organized in Battle Creek in April 1918.
The record group, only partially processed, consists of convention books which are scrapbooks containing programs of annual conventions, charters, and miscellaneous printed materials. In addition, there are minutes of the board of managers and of the state board, treasurer's records, general scrapbooks, and published materials.
Subjects:
Education--Michigan.; Kalamazoo (Mich.); Parents' and teachers' associations--Michigan.; Schools--Michigan.
Contributors:
Parents and Teachers Association. Kalamazoo County Council (Mich.)
Genre Terms:
Scrapbooks.
- Organizational records
  - Convention Books, 1918-1937 (Box 1)
  - Convention Books, 1938-1944 (Box 2)
  - Convention Books, 1945-1951 (Box 3)
  - District Books (1-5) (Box 3)
  - District Books (6-8) (Box 4)
  - Bulletins of the Michigan Branch, 1921-1951 (Box 4)
  - Minutes, 1918-1945 (Box 5)
  - Minutes, 1945-1954 (Box 6)
  - Treasurers' Reports, 1940-1952 (Box 6)
  - Procedure Books, 1922-1943 (Box 7)
  - Literature Books, 1919-1925 (Box 7)
  - Annual Reports, 1931-1954 (Box 7)
  - National Bulletins, 1935-1954 (Box 8)
  - National Publications (Box 8)
  - National Convention Materials (Box 8)
  - State Convention Materials (Box 9)
  - Historians Procedure Books, 1927-1944 (Box 9)
  - Historical Data, 1891-1951 (Box 10)
  - State Founders Day, 1939-1940 (Box 10)
  - Parent Education Institute (Box 10)
  - Publicity Material, 1948-1949 (Box 10)
  - State Chairman's Book, 1921-1932 (Box 10)
  - Conferences and Institutes, 1924-1936 (Box 11)
  - Life Members (Box 11)
  - Letterheads and Membership Cards (Box 11)
  - Michigan National Chairmen (Box 11)
  - District Four Records, 1934-1942 (Box 11)
  - Scrapbooks (Box 11)
  - Scrapbooks (Box 12)
  - Scrapbooks (Box 13)
  - Scrapbooks (Box 14)
  - Scrapbook of contribution receipts (Volume 1)
  - Scrapbook of press clippings, 1942-1944 (Volume 2)
  - Scrapbook of exhibit material, 1937-1938 (Volume 3)
  - Thirty-fifth Annual Convention Scrapbook, 1952 (Volume 4)
  - Thirty-sixth Annual Convention Scrapbook, 1953 (Volume 5)
  - Thirty-seventh Annual Convention Scrapbook, 1954 (Volume 6)
  - Minutes, 1945-1960 (Box 15)
  - State Chairman's Books, 1932-1939 (Box 16)
  - State Convention Materials (Box 16)
  - Historical Materials (Box 16)
  - Treasurers Records, 1952-1958 (Box 16)
  - Scholarships Awarded, 1957-1958 (Box 16)
  - Scholarships Awarded, 1958-1959 (Box 16)
  - Secretary's Book, 1951-1955 (Box 17)
  - Miscellanea (Box 17)
  - Records of the Kalamazoo County Council, 1927-1953 (Box 18)